const bis = [ // Bureau of Indian Standards
// Bureau of Indian Standards MCQ |MCQ No. 26| FSSAI MCQ. (Feb 20, 2022)
{ // 11
    question: "Which of the following BIS standards have been framed for Microscopic slips & Slides specification?",
    answers: ["IS 1470", "IS 3099", "IS 9396", "IS 2057"],
    correct: "IS 3099"
},
{ // 10
    question: "Which of the following BIS standards have been framed for Aluminum cans & Beverages?",
    answers: ["IS 2347", "IS 14407", "IS 15205", "IS 5445"],
    correct: "IS 14407"
},
{ // 9
    question: "Which of the following BIS standards have been framed for Sanitary cans for Food and Drinks?",
    answers: ["IS 3099", "IS 9396", "IS 1470", "IS 1501"],
    correct: "IS 9396"
},
{ // 8
    question: "Bureau of Indian Standards (BIS) is the National Standards Body of India and it comes under which department?",
    answers: ["Department of Consumer Affairs", "Department of Commerce", "Public health department", "None of the above"],
    correct: "Department of Consumer Affairs"
},
{ // 7
    question: "FSSAI said that no person should manufacture, sell or exhibit for sale, packaged drinking water and mineral water except under Bureau of Indian Standards (BIS) certification mark, since when has it effective?",
    answers: ["August 11, 2011", "April 1, 2018", "April 1, 2021", "May 1, 2020"],
    correct: "April 1, 2021"
},
{ // 6
    question: "Which of the following statement is not correct?",
    answers: ["ISI mark, BIS mark and Eco-mark are issued by the Bureau of Indian standard", "BIS hallmark is given only to gold jewellary", "Indian organic is a certification mark for organically framed food", "Bureau of Indian Standard is the national standard body of India"],
    correct: "BIS hallmark is given only to gold jewellary"
},
{ // 5
    question: "Who was the first Director of BIS?",
    answers: ["Sh. Rohit Kumar", "Sh. S. K. Sen", "Dr. A. N. Ghosh", "Dr. Lal C. Verman"],
    correct: "Dr. Lal C. Verman"
},
{ // 4
    question: "Which of the following BIS standards have been framed for packaged drinking water?",
    answers: ["IS 13252", "IS 14543", "IS 3099", "IS 14407"],
    correct: "IS 14543"
},
{ // 3
    question: "BIS certification for Packaged drinking water is:",
    answers: ["Binding Regulation", "Obligatory Standard", "Voluntary Standard", "Mandatory Standard"],
    correct: "Mandatory Standard",
    description: "1 April 2021 FSSAI made BIS certification for packaged drinking water as mandatory and before that it was a voluntary standard"
},
{ // 2
    question: "Which ministry issued the Eco-Mark?",
    answers: ["Ministry of Consumer affairs", "Ministry of Agriculture and Farmers welfare", "Ministry of Environment and Forest", "Ministry of Health and Family welfare"],
    correct: "Ministry of Environment and Forest",
    description: "Eco-Mark is a certification mark issued by BIS for products which are ecologically safe and adheres to the standards prescribed by the BIS. [However it was first issued in 1991 by Ministry of Environment and Forests]"
},
{ // 1
    question: "How many members in BIS are from Scientific and Research Institution, Technical, Education and Professional Organization?",
    answers: ["1 Member", "3 Member", "2 Member", "4 Member"],
    correct: "3 Member"
},

]